# **Becca King**

#### TITLE

Full-Stack Web Developer with Journalism Experience

# CONTACT

216-570-0627 rebecca.lynne.king@gmail.com Cleveland, OH 44102

# WEBSITE

rebeccaking.info

# **SKILLS**

JavaScript
JavaScript libraries (jQuery,
Parsley, React)
CSS
CSS preprocessors (Less)
HTML5
Progress OpenEdge
Microsoft SQL Server
Google Tag Manager and Google
Analytics
Git version control

# **EDUCATION**

General Assembly Software Engineering Certificate

> Miami University Bachelor of Science Kinesiology, Environmental Science University Honors Program

E.W. Scripps School of Journalism,
Ohio University
Master of Science
Completed two years of
coursework before leaving out of
medical necessity.

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a full-stack web developer with a background in journalism, and I am passionate about creating engaging online experiences for diverse audiences. I've worked closely with news editors, information technologists, designers, and e-commerce experts.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Amerimark Direct, LLC, Web Developer

Middleburg Heights, OH - Nov 2020 - Current

- Developed front and back end solutions using HTML5, Less, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Progress OpenEdge, and Git version control.
- Completed training in React, SQL, and web accessibility.
- Contributed to the redesign of five sites to make each responsive and reduce reliance upon third parties.

### Self-employed, Freelance Writer

Jan 2020 - Current

- Wrote magazine articles for *Teen Vogue* and *LGBTQ Nation*.
- Researched and reported original news stories for *The Athens News* and *The Athens Messenger*.
- Worked as a ghostwriter for We Write Blog Posts, later promoted to an editing position.

# North Coast Media, Web Developer

Cleveland, OH - Jan 2020 - Jul 2020

• Full stack development of websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, iQuery, Git, WordPress, PHP, SQL, Google Tag Manager.

# Ohio University, Graduate Assistant in Journalism

Athens, OH - Aug 2017 - May 2019

- Studied the fundamentals of online journalism, communication law, and media economics to become a well-rounded professional in the journalism field.
- Worked as a research assistant in journalism for varied university departments.
- Received mentorship from top professionals in the journalism industry.

# Americorps - La Puente Shelter, Community Educator and Volunteer Coordinator

Alamosa, CO - Aug 2016 - Jan 2017

- Created news and radio press releases on behalf of a rural homeless shelter.
- Gathered and edited stories for and designed a 32-page storybook on behalf of the organization. Used Indesign and Adobe Photoshop.